Laís Meuchi

• Cuiabá - Mato Grosso - Brazil

Ø laismeuchi.github.io

in laismeuchi

About

I have a degree in Computer Science and have been working in the IT field for over 14 years. In recent years I have focused on concepts and tools in the area of Big Data for Data Engineering, where I deepened my knowledge in Python, Spark and Databricks, with the aim of contributing to the optimization of data acquisition, processing and storage processes.

Experience __

This is a summarized version of my professional experiences, if you want to see the full version, just access my profile on Linkedin .

Data Engineer, Compass.uol

Nov 2024 – Present

- Development and management of data pipelines on Azure: Setting up and maintaining Data Lakes using Azure Storage Account, implementing data ingestion, transformation, and organization processes following the layered architecture (bronze, silver, gold).
- Data processing with Databricks: Developing PySpark and SQL scripts for data cleaning, transformation, and enrichment, ensuring high performance and scalability of processes.
- Integration of data from multiple sources: Collecting data from various systems, applying business rules, and delivering optimized formats for analysis teams and report generation.

BI Analyst, Governo do Estado de Mato Grosso

Nov 2023 - Nov 2024

- Development and maintenance of Power BI dashboards, ensuring the best storytelling practices.
- Dimensional modeling using Star Schema to ensure best Power BI practices.
- Development and maintenance of Python scripts to carry out ETL processes, used to obtain data from external sources and make the necessary transformations before using them as a Power BI source.

Data Engineer, Amaggi

Jan 2022 - Nov 2023

- Data Lake development and maintenance in the Azure environment using Storage Account for storage and Databricks (PySpark and SQL) for data processing with medallion architecture.
- Development of a data pipeline that combines information from various sources, applying the necessary business rules, making them available in the gold layer, thus reducing the time spent by users generating reports they use in their daily routines.
- · Creation of jobs in Databricks to perform daily processing, in addition to monitoring daily execution and making adjustments in the event of an error.

Product Owner, Amaggi

Apr 2021 – Jan 2022

- Maintenance and refinement of the backlog of data product demands, passing demands on to data engineers.
- Maintenance and refinement of the backlog of demands for the Farmer Credit product using Azure Boards.
- · Alignment with other internal teams regarding integrations and dependencies between products.

BI Analyst, LM Developer

Sep 2020 - Nov 2023

- Development and maintenance of Power BI dashboards, ensuring the best storytelling practices.
- Development and maintenance of Python scripts that carried out the data extraction process from public sources.
- Development and maintenance of SQL scripts, in MySQL database, used for the ETL process of the customers' Data Warehouse.

Education _____

FATEC SENAI MT, MBA in Project Managment Sep 2019 – Sep 2021

Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso, Database Specialization Sep 2013 – Sep 2015

Universidade Federal de São Carlos, Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Jan 2007 – Dec 2010

Certifications _____

Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate - Databricks

Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark 3.0 - Databricks

Fabric Data Engineer Associate (DP-700) - Microsoft

Azure Data Engineer Associate (DP-203) - Microsoft

Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900) - Microsoft

Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)- Microsoft

GitHub Foundations - GitHub

Professional Scrum Master - Scrum.Org

Skills _____

Data Engineer: Databricks, Apache Spark, Azure Data Factory, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure Stream Analytics.

Programming Languages: Python, SQL.

BI Tools: Power BI, Pentaho. **Databases:** SQL Server, MySQL.

Clouds: focusing on Azure, with basic knowledge of AWS and GCP.

CI/CD: Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps.

Project Managment: Agile, Scrum and SAFE methodologies.

Languages _____

English: advanced level.